迈克 · 诺斯: 当与未知数打交道时，先回到这个话题。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: When working with unknowns,
going back to that topic for a moment.
有一件事让我很困扰
There's one thing about this
that kinda bugs me, and
这个例子说明了。
that is illustrated by this example.
所以我们有一个值 aa，也就是未知数 bb,
So we have a value aa,
which is unknown, bb,
另一种未知的，但是完全不同的类型。
another unknown, but
a completely different type.
实际上我们没有得到一个类型错误。
And it's actually like we're
not getting a type error here.
因此，任何未知都可以指定给任何其他未知。
So any unknown can be assigned
to any other unknown.
这是因为它是一个顶级类型。
And it's because it's a top type.
它就像一个任何，它是一种不透明的任何。
It's just like an any,
it's sort of an opaque any.
我们看不到里面的东西，但它可以装下任何它想要的东西。
We can't see into it but
it can hold whatever it wants.
所以很容易得到一对不同的不透明值混合在一起
So it's very easy to get a couple sort
of different opaque values mixed up and
彼此交织在一起。
intertwined with each other.
所以，我要给你们一个替代方案
So, I'm gonna give you
an alternate solution that for
Me it’s a little more involved but
me it's a little more involved but
这个想法更安全，更直观。
the idea is a lot safer and
a lot more intuitive.
这被称为品牌类型。
And this is called branded types.
所以我要创建一个具有特殊属性名的接口
So I'm just gonna create an interface
that has a special property name
不太可能与任何其他物体重叠。
that is very unlikely to overlap with
anything any other object might have.
我有一个功能叫做品牌和非品牌。
And I have a function called brand and
unbrand.
我在这里做的是，通常这是不安全的，好吗？
What I'm doing here is,
typically this would be unsafe, all right?
这就是所谓的选角
This is called casting, and
它是你强迫一个值被视为特定类型的地方。
it is where you're forcing a value
to be regarded as a particular type.
我在这里传递一个字符串
So I'm passing a string in here, and
我强迫它到顶端类型未知，或者你可以做任何在这里。
I'm forcing it to a top type unknown,
or you could do any here.
然后强迫布兰德达。
And then forcing it to BrandedA.
如果我们不做这个中间步骤，我们就会变成这样，因为
If we did not do this intermediate
step we'd be all that because
这种类型之间没有重叠。
there is no overlap between this types.
我们使一个字符串看起来类似于
We're making a string
look to type script like
上面有特殊属性的物体。
an object with a special property on it.
然后我们有另一个匹配函数，进行逆变换。
And then we have another matching
function that does the inverse transform.
所以我们可以传递这些东西，它们看起来不像是绳子。
So we can pass this things around and
they dont look like strings.
没有人可以像字符串一样使用它，这就是优势。
Nobody is ever gonna be able to use this
like a string, here is the advantage.
首先，我要确保我们都同意这是不透明的，对吧？
So number one, I wanna make sure
we agree it's opaque, right?
我们没有看到这是一个字符串，我们不能用它来做字符串的东西。
We don't see that this is a string,
we can't do string stuff with it.
但是如果我们有另一种类型，这是一样的,
But if we had another type, and
this is just the same thing,
只是一个不同的属性键和值。
just a different property key and value.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们可以创造品牌价值，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We can create
branded values, right?
Brandb 用一个带有 abc 属性的对象来说明。
BrandB takes an object with a property
called abc, just to illustrate.
你可以用任何你喜欢的类型来做这件事。
You can do this with
whatever type you want.
迈克 · 诺斯: 但这才是吸引人的地方。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: But
this is the appealing part.
因为这是两种不同的品牌类型，有两种不同的属性。
Because these are two different branded
types with two different properties.
这个以 a 结尾，这个以 b 结尾。
Here this one ends with A,
this one ends with B.
你永远不能把他们弄糊涂。
You can never get them confused.
它们是两种不同的结构。
They're two different structures.
这两者之间不会有结构上的匹配。
There will not be a structural
match between these.
所以我们隐藏了这个值的原始身份。
So we've hidden away the original
identity of what this value is.
我们已经使它们不可互换。
We've made it so
that they're not interchangeable.
你不能无意中混合了不打上品牌的功能,
You can't accidentally mix
the unbranding functions,
这样就可以恢复原来的价值。
which will recover the original value.
但是如果你这样做了，你可以通过非品牌回到你最初的价值观
But you can get back to your original
values through the unbrand if you do it
正确地。
correctly.
所以，这几乎就像取一个值
So, it's almost like taking a value and
把它装进信封，然后包装起来。
putting it in an envelope and
packaging it up.
这就像你邮寄重要文件的信封一样。
It's like those envelopes you'd
mail an important document in.
你看不到里面的内容，但是上面有个标记，所以
Where you can't see the contents,
but it sort of has a stamp on it, so
你知道这是那个人写的，只有他们才能重新打开。
you know this came from that person and
only they can open it back up again.
那么，我马上就回答你的问题。
So, I'll get to your question in a second.
这里我唯一的建议是，确保代码中只有一个地方
My only tip here is, make sure that
there's only one place in your code
你正在做你的品牌和你的品牌。
where you're doing your branding and
your unbranding.
只有这样你才能完全确定没有人窥视这个东西,
That is the way you can be absolutely
sure nobody is peeking inside this thing,
或访问试图访问其原始值。
or accessing trying to
access its original value.
迈克 · 诺斯: 将铸件朝一个方向浇注到不透明的结构上
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Having the cast in one
direction to the opaque structure and
返回到相同的作业描述符模块。
back in the same job descriptor module.
如果你想改变现状,
That allows you if you
wanted to change things up,
你可以移除这个属性的关键，你可以在一个位置做出改变。
you could remove this property key and
you could make changes in one location.
因为没有其他人可以和它进行有意义的互动,
And because nobody else can interact
with it in a meaningful way,
你不需要改变其他任何东西。
you shouldn't have to alter
much of anything else.
你有什么问题吗？
Did you have a question?
演讲者2: 是的，这样做和使用一个物体有什么区别
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah, what is the point of
doing it this way versus using an object
然后在里面做私人侦探？
and doing a private inside of it?
Mike North: Privates 只能在类实例上使用。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Privates can only
be used on class instances.
演讲者2: 好的，这是什么？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay, so this was?
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以，我的意思是，你可以那样做，但那意味着
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So, I mean, you could
do things that way, but that would mean
这个类必须公开一种方法，把原始值返回出来。
that the class would have to expose a way
of getting that original value back out.
所以我特别用它来生成 ID。
So I use this, in particular,
for ID generation.
如果我在我的应用中有一打不同类型的实体，并且
Where if I've got a dozen different
type of entities in my app, and
我要发出身份证明我要确保它们都来自我的身份识别生成器,
I'm issuing IDs, and I wanna make sure
they're all coming from My ID generator,
不是普通的绳子，是这个。
it's not just any string it's this.
现在，我将创建一个品牌类型。
Now, I will create a branded type.
所以你可以肯定这就是原点。
So you can be sure like
this is the origin.
这是整个应用程序中唯一一个返回类型的函数
It's the only function in the whole
app that will return to type with this
结构。
structure.
当需要将这个或那个序列化到 JSON 时，这是一个谎言。
When it comes time to serialize this or
that to JSON, this here is a lie.
这是下面的实际类型，每当所有类型都编译离开时,
This is the real type underneath, and
whenever all of the types compile away,
你的代码将完全按照原来的方式运行，但是
your code will run exactly as
it would otherwise run, but
我只是想让你别插手这件事。
this is just a way of saying
hands off this thing.
好像我要用类型系统来隐藏这个本质似的
Like I'm gonna use the type system
as a way to hide the nature of this
只要有人想戳它，它就有价值。
value from anyone who would
care to try to poke at it.
再说一次，这与安全无关。
And again, it's not about security.
这是关于阻止开发人员相互交织
It's about discouraging
developers from intertwining
他们自己的私人部分，你的代码。
themselves with private
parts of your code.
作为一个图书馆作者，我想确保我可以削减
As a library author I want
to make sure that I can cut
修改了我的代码的新版本。
new releases with changes to my code.
我不会伤害其他人的。
And I'm not gonna break
a lot other people.
这是一种划清界限的方法，不要用这个,
And this is a way of sort of drawing
a clean line, don't use this,
我故意让事情变得困难。
I'm deliberately making it difficult.